[ 
{"question": "The government had recently launched central Equipment Identity Register portal. It operates under which department?", 
"options": ["A. Department of Science and Technology", "B. Department of Telecom", "C. Department of Biotechnology", "D. Department of Public Enterprise"], "answer": "B. Department of Telecom"}
, {"question": "From which Indian organization, the four personnel have been selected for training in Russia for the Gaganyaan Mission, that is going to be launched in 2022?", 
"options": ["A. ISRO", "B. IAF", "C. MARCOS", "D. Indian Navy"], "answer": "B. IAF"}
, {"question": "ISRO is to set up its second launch port in Tamilnadu for SSLV. What does SSLV stand for?", 
"options": ["A. Space Satellite Launch Vehicle", "B. Speed Satellite Launch Vehicle", "C. Small Satellite Launch Vehicle", "D. Solar Satellite Launch Vehicle"], "answer": "C. Small Satellite Launch Vehicle"}
, {"question": "Which state has recently declared 2020 as the year of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and has signed MoUs with tech firms for AI research?", 
"options": ["A. Andhra Pradesh", "B. Telengana", "C. Odisha", "D. Assam"], "answer": "B. Telengana"}
, {"question": "Which technology company has recently launched the new version of its ‘Edge Chromium’ browser for both Mac and Windows platforms?", 
"options": ["A. Google", "B. Microsoft", "C. Mozilla", "D. Apple"], "answer": "B. Microsoft"}
, {"question": ".Paperless licensing process for petroleum service stations has been launched through Petroleum and Explosives Safety Organisation (PESO). PESO comes under the aegis of which ministry?", 
"options": ["A. Ministry of Petroleum and Natural Gas", "B. Ministry of Commerce and Industry", "C. Ministry of Road Transport and Highways", "D. Ministry of Home Affairs"], "answer": "B. Ministry of Commerce and Industry"}
, {"question": "Which international smartphone firm recently signed an MoU with IIT- Hyderabad for Research and Development projects?", 
"options": ["A. Xiaomi", "B. OPPO", "C. Huawei", "D. Vivo"], "answer": "B. OPPO"}
, {"question": "The Daniel K. Inouye Solar Telescope (DKIST), the world’s largest solar telescope, has recently captured the highest-resolution image of which celestial body?", 
"options": ["A. Black hole", "B. Sun", "C. Icarus", "D. Flying Saucer galaxy"], "answer": "B. Sun"}
, {"question": "A National level Rural Technical Festival called ‘Antahpragnya 2020’ was recently organised in which Indian state/UT?", 
"options": ["A. Ladakh", "B. New Delhi", "C. Telangana", "D. Odisha"], "answer": "C. Telangana"}
, {"question": "Global code hosting platform GitHub, which recently launched its operations in India, is owned by which technological company?", 
"options": ["A. Google", "B. Amazon", "C. Apple", "D. Microsoft"], "answer": "D. Microsoft"}
, {"question": "Which global technology company recently announced a $1 million grant to promote news literacy in India?", 
"options": ["A. Microsoft", "B. Facebook", "C. Apple", "D. Google"], "answer": "D. Google"}
, {"question": "Which Indian fin-tech company has recently launched a point-of-sale (POS) device for smaller merchants?", 
"options": ["A. PhonePe", "B. Mobikwik", "C. Paytm", "D. BharatPe"], "answer": "C. Paytm"}
, {"question": "A new natural gas field named ‘Jebel Ali gas field’ with 80 trillion cubic feet of gas resources, was recently discovered in which country?", 
"options": ["A. Venezuela", "B. United Arab Emirates", "C. Qatar", "D. Iran"], "answer": "B. United Arab Emirates"}
, {"question": "‘Yodhavu’ (Warrior), a mobile application for curbing drug menace, is an initiative of which state?", 
"options": ["A. Karnataka", "B. Kerala", "C. Andhra Pradesh", "D. Telangana"], "answer": "B. Kerala"}
, {"question": "What is the name of the new satellite, scheduled to be launched by the ISRO on March 5, 2020?", 
"options": ["A. GISAT-1", "B.  GISAT-3", "C. GISAT-7", "D. GISAT-11"], "answer": "A. GISAT-1"}
, {"question": "The biggest explosion seen in the universe since the Big Bang have recently been discovered using the Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope (GMRT). Where is the GMRT located?", 
"options": ["A. Cochin", "B. Pune", "C. Thiruvananthapuram", "D. Hyderabad"], "answer": "B. Pune"}
, {"question": "The mobile application ‘Humsafar’, which was in news recently, is associated with which service?", 
"options": ["A. Ride-hailing", "B. Door Delivery of Fuel", "C. Door-Delivery of Medicines", "D. Booking Flight tickets"], "answer": "B. Door Delivery of Fuel"}
, {"question": "Google is set to launch its second cloud region in which Indian city?", 
"options": ["A. Gurugram", "B. Hyderabad", "C. Bengaluru", "D. Delhi"], "answer": "D. Delhi"}
, {"question": "‘Whole Genome Sequencing (WGS)’, which was seen in news recently, is associated with research in which field?", 
"options": ["A. Agriculture", "B. Genetics", "C. Environment", "D. Energy"], "answer": "B. Genetics"}
, {"question": "What does the term ‘Necurs’ represent, which was seen in news recently?", 
"options": ["A. A virus", "B. A botnet", "C. A bitcoin", "D. A worm"], "answer": "B. A botnet"}
]